<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-10T22:28:53-06:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Jared Sackett</title><subtitle>This is not a clever tagline</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dune Review</title><link href="/blog/2018/02/21/Dune-Review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dune Review" /><published>2018-02-21T05:01:19-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-21T05:01:19-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/02/21/Dune-Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/02/21/Dune-Review/">&lt;p&gt;I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert roughly a week ago, but haven’t had time to do a full review until now, so here it goes… Spoilers ahead if you haven’t read it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed the book, but there were definitely some elements I really didn’t like. I enjoyed the exploration of political power and pride, the characters were wonderful, and the worldbuilding was very well done. I didn’t really enjoy the idea of Feudalism in space as much as I thought I might, the pacing definitely felt like it was from 1965, and I wish the author had spent time on different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s elaborate on the good: The exploration of political power was very interesting, I enjoyed reading about how the different houses worked with and against each other, and how the emperor tied into it at the end. Part of this ends up being a con, but I’ll explore that in a little bit. The idea of a mentat was quite interesting too, since that’s often how people in the 50s and 60s seemed to have perceived computers: As something that was given a bunch of input, and then could be asked questions to get output. That is essentially what they are today, however the type of input and output is a little different. Today it’s a little more raw than it it was in this book. The mentats being used as tools for the houses was an interesting thing as well, since while they try to suppress their emotions (like Vulcans from Star Trek), they do have them and can be bent with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters were fantastic in this book. I really wanted to see Paul gain power since we believe he’ll use it for good, and was happy when at the end of the book he achieved this. I really got a sense of who Paul was by what he did and how he thought, and it’s very easy to forget that his character is only 15-17 years old. His mother was someone we really cared about throughout the book as well, and it was interesting to see the conflict between her motherly desires, the desires of the Bene Gesserit, and her position of power. The Baron was a fantastic villain, since the dichotomy of love vs hate being tools of power was very apparent in him vs the Duke (and later Paul). I enjoyed seeing the Baron use people to gain his goals because it adds to the hate we have for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This aspect is a double-edged sword, because when it’s used by characters we really want to like, it leaves a sour taste in our mouth. That’s one of the main things I really didn’t enjoy about this book: The good guys manipulate people to get power too. Maybe not quite as badly as the bad guys, but they do do it. I especially dislike how Paul married the princess at the end for power, because while she may be in a position of power, she’s a human being who desires love as well, and by Paul marrying her he takes away the option for her to marry someone who loves her. Unfortunately, this seems like a side effect of the feudal society in which the book takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I really didn’t like how this book spends it’s time. I would have appreciated some more concise descriptions of the world and creatures, since the ones given were often hard to understand and/or remember. The characters definitely don’t talk or think in phrasing that normal people use, it’s more like how in classic movies the characters use extra flowery phrasing to sound more classy and polished. This can be nice, and I do appreciate it, but I think it’s a little overused in parts of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, those are my thoughts on it. It’s a good read, but by todays standards might seem a little slow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I finished reading Dune by Frank Herbert roughly a week ago, but haven’t had time to do a full review until now, so here it goes… Spoilers ahead if you haven’t read it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m reading books a lot now!</title><link href="/blog/2018/02/05/Beginning-Book-Reviews/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I'm reading books a lot now!" /><published>2018-02-05T10:52:35-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T10:52:35-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/02/05/Beginning-Book-Reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/02/05/Beginning-Book-Reviews/">&lt;p&gt;So lately, I’ve taken to reading a lot. I always have enjoyed reading books, but recently my interest and time spent doing it has increased significantly. Don’t be concerned, I’m not an addict. Please don’t call my Mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, being as ADHD as I am (officially actually, as of my childhood anyway), I can’t just read one book, so I’m in the middle of several. Here they are, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inception and Philosophy: Because It’s Never Just a Dream&lt;/em&gt; by David Kyle Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos&lt;/em&gt; by Jordan Peterson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowing God&lt;/em&gt; by J.I. Packer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bible&lt;/em&gt; by God (It might take me a while to review this one, there’s a lot going on here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I’m not actually going to review the Bible. Who am I to do that anyway, that’s almost blasphemous just to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Here is my Master book list. All the books I want to read. It’s growing quite a bit. Some of the books are novels, others are non-fiction/philosophy, and others are a bit of the educational/self-help variety. Some of the novels are classics, Sci-Fi, Fantasy, and some of them are just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these books are pretty hard reads. Until recently it seems, most novels had a TON of description, with lots of flowery language. I like myself a well constructed sentence, but when it’s so long I have to struggle to remember the beginning of it, that’s a bit much. I’m exaggerating a bit here, and since your mind is like a muscle I hope to get better at all this, but just in case for now, I will occasionally supplement my reading with SparkNotes or something similar, to make sure I don’t get lost. This isn’t cheating, it’s using your resources, as they say. &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20180205232255/https://i.pinimg.com/736x/42/c4/d8/42c4d80a29f7848043b9996769c4a700.jpg&quot;&gt;Who are the &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; anyway?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;master-book-list&quot;&gt;Master Book List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last updated: Feb 5, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;classic-novels&quot;&gt;Classic Novels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt; by Ray Bradbury*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt; by George Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brave New World&lt;/em&gt; by Aldous Huxley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/em&gt; by Gorge Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; by Jane Austen**&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Giver&lt;/em&gt; by Lois Lowry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Picture of Dorian Grey&lt;/em&gt; by Oscar Wilde&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;theologyphilosophy&quot;&gt;Theology/Philosophy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mere Christianity&lt;/em&gt; by C.S. Lewis*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Divorce&lt;/em&gt; by C.S. Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miracles&lt;/em&gt; by C.S. Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Screwtape Letters&lt;/em&gt; by C.S. Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Problem of Pain&lt;/em&gt; by C.S. Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life Together&lt;/em&gt; by Dietrich Bonhoeffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;education-self-help--science&quot;&gt;Education, Self-Help, &amp;amp; Science&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Personal MBA&lt;/em&gt; by Josh Kaufman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/em&gt; by Timothy Ferriss&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less&lt;/em&gt; by Greg McKeown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Power of Habit&lt;/em&gt; by Charles Duhigg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt; by Cal Newport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt; by Cal Newport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spark: The Revolutionary New Science of Exercise and the Brain&lt;/em&gt; by John J Ratey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Motivation Hacker&lt;/em&gt; by Nick Winter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&lt;/em&gt; Stephen R. Covey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brain Rules&lt;/em&gt; by John Medina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Productivity Project&lt;/em&gt; by Chris Bailey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daily Rituals: How Artists Work&lt;/em&gt; by Mason Currey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steal the Show&lt;/em&gt; by Michael Port&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sci-fifantasy-novels&quot;&gt;Sci-Fi/Fantasy Novels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaker for the Dead&lt;/em&gt; by Orson Scott Card*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Thrawn&lt;/em&gt; by Timothy Zahn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Children of Time&lt;/em&gt; by Adrian Tchaikovsky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt; by William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Victorian Internet&lt;/em&gt; by Tom Standage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Horse,the Wheel, and Language&lt;/em&gt; by David W. Anthony&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* Books I’ve already read, I just want to re-read them&lt;/em&gt;
** &lt;em&gt;Books I’ve partially read, and for whatever reason stopped&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please give me suggestions if there’s something that you think should be on this list! Not saying I’ll put it here for sure, but I definitely like ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">So lately, I’ve taken to reading a lot. I always have enjoyed reading books, but recently my interest and time spent doing it has increased significantly. Don’t be concerned, I’m not an addict. Please don’t call my Mom.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monkeyhole Rules</title><link href="/tutorial/2018/01/15/Monkey-In-The-Middle-Cornhole-Rules/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monkeyhole Rules" /><published>2018-01-15T06:46:21-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T06:46:21-06:00</updated><id>/tutorial/2018/01/15/Monkey-In-The-Middle-Cornhole-Rules</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tutorial/2018/01/15/Monkey-In-The-Middle-Cornhole-Rules/">&lt;p&gt;For New Years Eve I was hanging with some friends, and we sort of invented a new game, which is a cross between Monkey in the Middle and Cornhole. I’m calling it &lt;em&gt;Monkeyhole&lt;/em&gt; because it sounds good and makes sense. It’s pretty intense, and if you play it right there can be some strategy to it! I promised I’d make a write-up of some rules, including how you win (because we hadn’t figured that out yet), so here they are, albeit a bit late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game requires either 3 people, or two teams and a third person, but the amount of players &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be odd. I’m going to assume 3 people to start, and then I’ll explain how it can be modified for teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two teams: Red and Blue (or whatever bean bags you’re using), and three players. The goal of the game is to be on the winning team and not in the middle, when a number of points are reached (or you could do it via time as well). I’ll refer to the people throwing the bean bags as the throwers, and the monkey as the monkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game begins with the two throwers standing on either side of the first board. The monkey is in the middle of course. The throwers take turns attempting to throw the bags onto the opposite board, just like normal Cornhole. The monkey attempts to block and/or catch the bags as they go by. If the monkey catches a bag, the monkey switches places with whoever threw it. The caught bag is left on the floor. This is how you can switch teams during this game, and it’s where some of the strategy comes in. Maybe you decide to try and catch only the red bean bags, hoping that you can score some points for that team and that you’ll be throwing when the game ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoring is like normal Cornhole: When the throwers run out of bags, the amount of points on the board is added up and the difference is added to the total for whichever team: A bean bag on the board is 1 point, and one in the hole is 3. Gently lift up the board if there are any bean bags that are partially on. If they stay on, they count. For example: Red has 2 bean bags on the board (2 points), Blue has one in the hole for 3 points. 3-2 = 1, so Blue gets 1 point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is over when either team reaches 11 points (or whatever you feel like, as long as it’s odd), or when a predetermined time runs out. The thrower on the winning team wins!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To play with more than 3 people, one person is the monkey and people on each team rotate every throw or every round (when someone runs out of bags), depending on how many people and how patient they are. This should be decided prior to play of course.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">For New Years Eve I was hanging with some friends, and we sort of invented a new game, which is a cross between Monkey in the Middle and Cornhole. I’m calling it Monkeyhole because it sounds good and makes sense. It’s pretty intense, and if you play it right there can be some strategy to it! I promised I’d make a write-up of some rules, including how you win (because we hadn’t figured that out yet), so here they are, albeit a bit late.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Star Wars VIII: The Last Jedi - SPOILER REVIEW</title><link href="/blog/2017/12/18/Star-Wars-VIII-The-Last-Jedi-Initial-Review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Star Wars VIII: The Last Jedi - SPOILER REVIEW" /><published>2017-12-18T18:20:44-06:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T18:20:44-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/12/18/Star-Wars-VIII-The-Last-Jedi-Initial-Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/12/18/Star-Wars-VIII-The-Last-Jedi-Initial-Review/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update Feb. 2018:&lt;/em&gt; I have discussed some of the film further with some friends who strongly disliked it, and while I still think it is a great film, I think my initial reaction to people disliking it so much was quite over simplified. I’ll leave it below, but know that I do see some ways the film might have been better, or a better Star Wars film, and that if you hold those opinions, more power to you! Having said all that, I still take issue with people saying it’s objectively bad, or an objectively bad Star Wars film, and it’s still among my favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPOILERS AHEAD!!! STOP NOW IF YOU DON’T WISH TO BE SPOILED!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just got back from seeing Star Wars Episode VIII: The Last Jedi and …. WOW!!! I absolutely love this movie. It’s right up there in the franchise, definitely top 3. It was a polarizing movie, and after spending time reading people’s reasons for disliking it online, I think I can understand where they’re coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I respectfully disagree with their opinion… Strongly disagree. In fact, there were really only two things that bothered me about this movie, so I’ll cover those first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why have Jedi Master Luke milk this weird… Thing? Honestly it was a little gross, and totally unnecessary to the story.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The humor at times seemed a bit forced (haha, puns), and marvel-ish. Most of the humor was very good, but I think they could have pulled back during some of the more serious moments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as to why I think this movie was so polarizing? I really think it comes down to &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you like Star Wars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Original Trilogy was heavily based around the archetypal hero’s journey. All the characters are there, you have Luke, the nobody from nowhere who discovers he’s a somebody with a very important ancestry and destined to save the Galaxy. You have Obi-Wan, who’s the old hermit wizard who trains the boy, and (literally) disappears when it’s time for the boy to stand on his own. You have the selfish jerk who eventually learns to care for other people and becomes a hero in his own right. And you have the funny characters that still move the plot along. All the parts are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prequel Trilogy was a bit… Different. While it has many faults in regards to poor dialogue, very annoying characters, and many other poor choices from a critic-of-film standpoint, as a story it was good. It had a lot going for it, and it really added to the Star Wars cannon. But, it was different. Really different. People didn’t want different, not like this. You have Anakin, who’s this hero, but falls. His mentor is unable to guide him well enough. The Jedi order, instead of being this holy, incorruptible order of wisdom, turns to war and lets their greatest enemy gain power right under their nose. Much of what we know about Star Wars is challenged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, you have the Sequel Trilogy. It is also quite a bit different. Instead of having archetypes, or anti-archetypes, we have un-archetypes. Rey turns out to have no important parentage (unless you are of the mindset that Kylo/Ben lied, which is a very high possibility). Luke turns out to have failed, but in a final show of immense force-power seeks to teach Ben Solo one final lesson. Kylo turns on his master, but instead of being a big side-change it’s a power grab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything about this movie completely changes your expectations. If you’re in it for the nostalgia (which means you likely love the Original Trilogy and hate the prequels), there’s a good chance you might not have liked this movie. That’s okay. If you thought episode VII seemed too much like a remake, but still wanted more of the archetypes, you might not like this movie either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for me? I love the fresh perspective it brings on not just the Star Wars universe, but on my view of humanity as a whole. Rey is an example of how where you come from doesn’t have to define your destiny. In a world where people are turning back to their race, political party, and sex as the source of their identity, in this movie her character chooses to let go of all that and pursue a path forward, letting go of the past. Or is it? Episode IX might have other ideas, and that’s okay. I look forward to seeing what those are!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Update Feb. 2018: I have discussed some of the film further with some friends who strongly disliked it, and while I still think it is a great film, I think my initial reaction to people disliking it so much was quite over simplified. I’ll leave it below, but know that I do see some ways the film might have been better, or a better Star Wars film, and that if you hold those opinions, more power to you! Having said all that, I still take issue with people saying it’s objectively bad, or an objectively bad Star Wars film, and it’s still among my favorites.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Science and Christianity aren’t at odds</title><link href="/blog/2017/12/03/Why-Science-and-Christianity-arent-at-odds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Science and Christianity aren't at odds" /><published>2017-12-03T07:54:31-06:00</published><updated>2017-12-03T07:54:31-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/12/03/Why-Science-and-Christianity-arent-at-odds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/12/03/Why-Science-and-Christianity-arent-at-odds/">&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time on the internet, especially on sites like reddit and YouTube. I’ve observed on these sites that a large amount of people think one can’t be both religious and scientific. Adherence to a religious belief instantly discredits you from anything you have to say because you’re “delusional” and/or a “science-denier”. I will attempt to argue that this is most certainly not the case, and that one can practice religion (in my case Christianity) while still being scientific. One must simply understand the scope of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-purpose-of-science-and-religion&quot;&gt;The purpose of Science and Religion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science and Religion are both tools for discovering truth. The truths they reveal are fundamentally different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For purposes of this argument, I will define science as anything discovered through proper use of the scientific method. The scientific method contains several steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask a question&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a hypothesis (or a well-researched guess)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design a procedure to test the hypothesis, attempting to remove as many extra variables as possible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use evidence from the procedure to arrive at a conclusion about the hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These steps have been designed to tell us truths about the physical, testable, world. Christianity on the other hand tells us truths about the spiritual world, as well as a few truths about the physical world. It is these physical truths that many site as reasons to disqualify the Bible, but what I don’t think they take into account are the fundamental limits of the scientific method, and the intended purpose for some of the religious truths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-assumptions-of-science&quot;&gt;The assumptions of Science&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the scientific method is that in order to work, it makes two assumptions, which are vital to understand when considering the broad picture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything can be explained through examination and testing of the physical world. For the purposes of Science anything outside the physical world doesn’t exist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The laws of nature and the physical world have never changed nor will they ever change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science makes these assumptions by necessity. If a scientist factors the metaphysical into experiments, that allows for an infinite amount of variables and explanations. Why did the apple fall to the ground? Easy, a metaphysical force wanted it to happen so it did. Or maybe the apple’s spirit wanted to be &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the ground. Obviously those conclusions aren’t very useful, nor are they testable. This is why when performing science, one must understand that they cannot account for the metaphysical, and as such any evidence they gather is under that assumption. It isn’t a bad assumption. I’d argue it’s a very useful assumption for the purposes that science usually has - that is, to discover things about the natural world that can be harnessed by mankind for good (or evil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second assumption science makes is that the laws of the physical world are immutable. This is also out of necessity for many of the same reasons as the first assumption are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to all of this is understanding that these assumptions &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; in place when doing science. Once this is understood, one can more accurately use the knowledge gained through this method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;reconciling-science-with-the-bible&quot;&gt;Reconciling Science with the Bible&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origin of the universe and humanity is one of the most polarizing issues, both between different groups of Christians and between Christians and Atheists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the solution to this problem is to recognize that science is most accurate when telling us about the present time, and any claims made about the pre-recorded past are subject to those two assumptions I mentioned earlier. I’m not suggesting we throw out all of those findings, but I am saying one can be a scientist or an intellectual and choose to disbelieve some of them. It just depends on which method one prefers for delivering truth. I’ve seen Science to be wrong quite often in the past, but many of the events predicted in the Bible have come to pass, and I personally choose to believe in the Bible when it indisputably clashes with scientific findings about the past. My actual beliefs regarding the age of the earth and how humanity came to be are quite nuanced, and I don’t want to cause a fight in the comment section, so I won’t discuss those here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-usefulness-of-biblical-statements-on-the-physical-world&quot;&gt;The usefulness of Biblical statements on the physical world&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Bible contains some statements about the universe that may be at odds with Science, It also contains commandments that align with Scientific findings, but are presented for different purposes. One of the easiest examples to see is in mosaic law regarding dietary restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God tells the Jews not to eat meat with blood still in it. We know through scientific findings that raw meat can be dangerous to consume due to germs which have congregated in the meat since the animal has been dead. The Jews didn’t have germ theory, but God was able to help protect them with that law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know today that certain types of meat are relatively safe to consume uncooked, and many modern day Christians enjoy rare steak. I believe God gave the Jews this dietary restriction for the additional purpose of unification and separation. He wanted His people to be distinct from the rest of the world, and dietary restrictions are a very effective way to do that. We see this purpose in most of the other ceremonial laws as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Science and the Bible can teach us truths about the world. It’s important to understand the purpose and limitations of both in order to arrive at what’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Please leave a comment below if you have any thoughts to add or discuss.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I spend a lot of time on the internet, especially on sites like reddit and YouTube. I’ve observed on these sites that a large amount of people think one can’t be both religious and scientific. Adherence to a religious belief instantly discredits you from anything you have to say because you’re “delusional” and/or a “science-denier”. I will attempt to argue that this is most certainly not the case, and that one can practice religion (in my case Christianity) while still being scientific. One must simply understand the scope of both.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mandatory First Post!</title><link href="/blog/2017/11/06/Mandatory-First-Post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mandatory First Post!" /><published>2017-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/11/06/Mandatory-First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/11/06/Mandatory-First-Post/">&lt;p&gt;So, I suppose this is the first post I’ll ever make. I’ve decided to make this site as an outlet for various thoughts I have, and to create a place for discussion regarding those. I plan to put some sort of comments system on here, but we’ll see what I can do. I may just recommend responding to what I put on here on your own blog, as I plan to respond to others here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from various rants and articles to discuss, I’ll occasionally be doing various productivity experiments and trying various things, all of which I’ll put on here for your entertainment!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">So, I suppose this is the first post I’ll ever make. I’ve decided to make this site as an outlet for various thoughts I have, and to create a place for discussion regarding those. I plan to put some sort of comments system on here, but we’ll see what I can do. I may just recommend responding to what I put on here on your own blog, as I plan to respond to others here.</summary></entry></feed>