<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-10T12:26:56-06:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Jared Sackett</title><subtitle>Jared's personal site. Christianity, Rants, productivity, discussions, nerdy stuff.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Abusive Relationship and the Car</title><link href="/blog/The-Abusive-Relationship-and-The-Car/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Abusive Relationship and the Car" /><published>2017-11-10T05:28:52-06:00</published><updated>2017-11-10T05:28:52-06:00</updated><id>/blog/The-Abusive-Relationship-and-The-Car</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/The-Abusive-Relationship-and-The-Car/">&lt;p&gt;God is amazing. God is perfect. Somehow he loves us when we’re definitely, definitely not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell pretty hard into an old sin habit the other day, as we’re all prone to do. Of course, once I fully realized what I had done I felt terrible, since it’s one of those sin habits that just doesn’t want to go away. I was praying to God asking for forgiveness, etc. when the full extent of his grace dawned on me. I remembered two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it’s a relationship, but since one of us is perfect and the other is far from it, it’s really an abusive relationship. We’re the abuser. Think about that for a sec.
&lt;strong&gt;It’s an abusive relationship in which &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; are the abuser.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does God continue to stay in this abusive relationship? It’s certainly not good for us to stay in those kinds of relationships. I think it’s because of how perfect and good God is. He can’t be dragged down by us. We add nothing to him, we take nothing from him. His grace just overflows into us. Through Jesus’ death on the cross, we’re saved from the penalty to our sin and somehow God is able to not only tolerate us, but love us and &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; us through it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is also our father, and he gives great gifts as he says. There’s an analogy I once heard somewhere that I will expound apon slightly, which is the other thing I remembered after I fell again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a father who, being incredibly wealthy, gives his son a sports car. The son loves the car, and loves to drive it, but sometimes he get’s a bit rowdy. Perhaps he’s just really had a rough day, or he’s feeling that teenage angst that we’ve all felt at one point. He drives a bit too fast, takes a turn a bit too fast, and crashes into a pole. He gets the car fixed, nobody is hurt, but it’s still pretty rough. One would think that he would learn from this and drive carefully, but instead, when his dad purchases a new car, he does it again, except this time going even faster. He thinks to himself “I can control it this time! I’m a better driver than I was then!”. Of course, he’s lying to himself. While he may be a better driver, he’s really just intoxicated with the adrenaline, the anger that he feels, the pain, whatever’s going on, that he crashes again, this time almost hurting someone in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet his dad fixes the car for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens several more times, each time increasing in damage. He totals the car several times, but his dad gives him new ones each time. His dad is fully aware of how his son will handle the car, but believes that eventually he will learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy starts to &lt;em&gt;break down&lt;/em&gt; here (haha puns), but I think it can be useful to think about God this way. He’s given us something, which we continue to abuse and hurt ourselves and sometimes others with, and while we have to live with the consiquences of our actions, he is graceful and merciful in how he repairs the damage we caused, and helps us grow along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">God is amazing. God is perfect. Somehow he loves us when we’re definitely, definitely not.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mandatory First Post!</title><link href="/blog/Mandatory-First-Post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mandatory First Post!" /><published>2017-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/blog/Mandatory-First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Mandatory-First-Post/">&lt;p&gt;So, I suppose this is the first post I’ll ever make. I’ve decided to make this site as an outlet for various thoughts I have, and to create a place for discussion regarding those. I plan to put some sort of comments system on here, but we’ll see what I can do. I may just recommend responding to what I put on here on your own blog, as I plan to respond to others here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from various rants and articles to discuss, I’ll occasionally be doing various productivity experiments and trying various things, all of which I’ll put on here for your entertainment!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">So, I suppose this is the first post I’ll ever make. I’ve decided to make this site as an outlet for various thoughts I have, and to create a place for discussion regarding those. I plan to put some sort of comments system on here, but we’ll see what I can do. I may just recommend responding to what I put on here on your own blog, as I plan to respond to others here.</summary></entry></feed>